## Yuanbo Xiangli

Tel: (+852) 55341509 / (+86) 13811767475 Email: ambie.xlyb@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

2019 – 2023 (expected) The Chinese University of Hong Kong

PhD in MMLab, Information Engineering

2017 – 2018 Oxford University

MSc in Computer Science

2013 – 2017 University of Nottingham

**BSc Honors Computer Science** 

### **SHORT BIO**

I am a 3rd year (2019-) Ph.D student in Multimedia Lab, Information Engineering, CUHK, supervised by Prof. Dahua Lin. My research interest lies in 3D computer vision and deep generative modeling. Currently, I am working on photorealistic and efficient city scenes reconstruction, manipulation and generation based on multi-source data, including satellite imagery, oblique photography, street view panoramas and urban planning information.

### **PUBLICATION**

- [1] Y. Xiangli, L. Xu, X. Pan, N. Zhao, A. Rao, C. Theobalt, B. Dai, D. Lin, "CityNeRF: Building NeRF at City Scale", arXiv preprint arXiv: 2112.05504, 2021.
- [2] L. Xu, <u>Y. Xiangli</u>, A. Rao, N. Zhao, B. Dai, Z. Liu, D. Lin, "BlockPlanner: City Block Generation with Vectorized Graph Representation," in *International Conference on Computer Vision 2021*.
- [3] Y. Xiangli, Y. Deng, B. Dai, C. C. Loy and D. Lin, "Real or Not Real, that is the Question," in *International Conference on Learning Representations 2020.* (Spotlight)
- [4] C. X. Lu, Y. Li, <u>Y. Xiangli</u> and Z. Li, "Nowhere to Hide: Cross-modal Identity Leakage between Biometrics and Devices," in *Proceedings of The Web Conference 2020.*
- [5] C. X. Lu, <u>Y. Xiangli</u>, P. Zhao, C. Chen, N. Trigoni and A. Markham, "Autonomous Learning of Speaker Identity and WiFi Geofence from Noisy Sensor Data," in *IEEE Internet of Things Journal*, 2019.
- [6] Y. Xiangli, C. X. Lu, P. Zhao, C. Chen, A. Markham, "iSCAN: automatic speaker adaptation via iterative cross-modality association," in *ISWC Adjunct, UniComp 2019*.
- [7] Y. Li, H. Deng, <u>Y. Xiangli</u>, Z. Yuan, C. Peng, and S. Lu, "In-device, runtime cellular network information extraction and analysis: demo," In *Proceedings of the 22nd Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (MobiCom '16)*. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 503-504, 2016.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CityNeRF Reconstruct city scenes at drastic multi-scale via Nerual Radiane Field (NeRF)

An attempt to bring NeRF to potentially city-scale scenes, which requires rendering drastically varied observations (level-of-detail and spatial coverage) at multiscales. It is an indispendible step towards efficient and realistic city-scale neural rendering in the future.

neural rendering in the rutu

**BlockPlanner** City block layout generation with vectorized graph representation

Using generative models to automatically learn from large amount of public urban planning data enables fast generation of batches of diverse and valid city block templates, which encourage more stakeholders and non-expertise to

participate in city design and planning. The vectorized representation is memory efficient and allows easy visualization and editing, e.g. global style transformation and local arrangement editing.

## **Realness GAN**Realness distribution guided Generative Adversarial Network (GAN)

The proposed realness distribution provides stronger guidance to the generator and encourages it to learn more diverse outputs. The proposed approach enables the simplest GAN structure to be able to synthesis high resolution portrait for the first time, with affordable computational overhead.

### SCAN+/iSCAN

Automatic inferring voice labels for speaker identification via ambient WiFi data The proposed framework leverages the abundant side-channel information provided by the ubiquitous IoT environment in mordern life, enabling the construction of an in-domain speaker recognition model with zero human enrollment. It can also be continuously updated through lifelong learning to fit changes in the user group.

### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

## 2020.3-2021.9 Compilation and composition of Information Technology

**Textbook (High School)** 

Author

Composed Chapter 14: Generative Modeling; participate in reviewing other chapters.

### 2019.2-2019.8 Sensetime

Research Intern

Worked with Dr. Bo Dai and Prof. Dahua Lin on realistic image synthesis with generative models.

### 2016 Summer Computer Science Department, the University of California, Los Angeles

Research Assistant

Worked with Dr. Yuanjie Li and Prof. Songwu Lu on project `MobileInsight', improving Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH) algorithm using physical layer bandwidth for smoother streaming.

### 2015.9-2016.6 Computer Science Department, University of Nottingham

Data Analyst and developer (android app `MentalSpace')

Worked with Prof. Max L. Wilson on electroencephalogram (EEG) data collection, analysis, and visualization.

# 2015 Summer Information Engineering Department, the Chinese U

## Information Engineering Department, the Chinese University of Hong Kong

Research Assistant

Worked with Prof. Chen Change Loy on image aesthetic assessment.

### **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

2021 Spring	Data Structure (Undergrad)
2019/20 Spring	Multimedia Coding and Processing (Undergrad)
2019/20/21 Fall	Problem Solving by Programming (Undergrad)

#### **SKILLS AND INSERTS**